David Watson

d@davidwatson.org

Created emerging technology playing advisor, coder, and founder building nimble environments from R&D labs to tech startups. Worked with interdisciplinary teams from two to two dozen artists, scientists, and philosophers scaling teams and sketches from prototypes into products and services.

Experience

2023-present Technical Consultant (1099) WYVERN Ltd

Modernized legacy code, culture resulting in better sustainability

2021 Technical Consultant (1099) Caterpillar

Catalyzed terrain visualization code ported from Intel to Xilinx

2020 Senior Member of Technical Staff (W-2) Carnegie Mellon University

Researched and Developed AI, HPC, and HCI in SEI Emerging Technology group

2018-2020 Software Engineering Specialist (W-2) Caterpillar Autonomy Lab

Collaborated with IT executives to move data storage provisioning to cloud native

2016-2018 Senior Software Developer (W-2) RealPage

Transformed legacy crawler into modern cloud native data pipeline

2015-2016 VP Product Development (W-2) Wellbridge Health

Sunset MVP and built API and production deployment; MAYA built UX/UI

2013-2014 Senior Software Developer(W-2) Forever

Prototyped MVP solo; developed 1.0-2.0 production with team of 4;

2011-2012 Senior Engineer W-2) SMaSh

Built conversational text interfaces with a team of 2

2010-2011 Software Development Manager(W-2) Wellspring Worldwide

Led team to transform legacy deployment to automated CI/CD pipeline

2009 Technical Consultant (1099) TenthRow

Developed live music experience streaming to fans worldwide

2008 Usability Consultant (1099) MAYA Design

Provided design feedback to MAYA Design on usability of Bayer Diabetes Glycemic Monitor

2008-2009 Project Engineer (W-2) Applied Perception

Ported GUI to OCU; Coded sonar parser/visualization bridging sensors->UI

2008 Technical Consultant (1099) Zenit Solutions

Designed and implemented python system to track inbound/outbound movers

2006-2007 UI Software Developer (W-2) Nomos

Wrote QA tests for Corvus radiotherapy product; Designed and Prototyped 4D UI/UX

2004-2006 Software Design Engineer (W-2) MAYA Design

Built AJAX stack on Python and NoSQL DB; built predecessor to Phillips Hue C#.net

2003-2004 *Cofounder (W-2) Cobind*

Designed, built, and shipped the Cobind Desktop to test the DIY Linux build tools

Education

- Duquesne University
 - **BS/BA** Coursework included Business, Computer Science, and Music

Continuing Education

- Git Foundations Workshop
 - Github
- Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT)
 - (CE) RDBMS and Internet Application Programming
- Programming Arduino Physical Pixels
 - Hack PGH

Awards

- Idea Foundry
 - Transformation Fellowship
- InfoWorld
 - Top 100 Award